A Guide to the Papers of William Faulkner 191?-1979
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of William Faulkner, 1919?-1979
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
9817-f
249 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access to the original manuscripts is restricted (to ensure the survival of the physically-delicate originals) to doctoral candidates at the dissertation stage of their programs, and to certain mature scholars and critics. These researchers must demonstrate need to see the originals that goes beyond the requirements of most routine research. A doctoral candidate at the dissertation stage, or other qualified researcher who believes that his or her work requires access to the originals must correspond with the Director of Special Collections prior to arrival at the Library to obtain permission for access.
Acquisition Information
Deposit of Jill Faulkner Summers, 1981 February 24 and 25
Alternative Form
Parts of the collection (autograph maps and Wild Palms manuscript and typescript) also available on Microfilm Reel #832
Organization
The collection is arranged in four series: I) The Wild Palms Material. II) Manuscripts. III) Correspondence. IV) Printed Material.
Contents List
- I. The Wild Palms Material
  - Front Boards n.d., 2 items
  - Autograph maps of Lafayette County, Mississippi, intended as frontispiece, 2 items
  - Wild Palms, Chapters [1-5], TMs (carbon), 161 p.
    - Chapter [1] pages 1-22a, 23 p.
    - Chapter [2], pages 23-31, 9 p.
    - Chapter [3], pages 32-66, 35 p.
    - Chapter [4], pages 67-90, 24 p.
    - Chapter [5], pages 70, 89a-158, 70 p.
  - Wild Palms Chapters [6-8], TMs (carbon), 150 p.
    - Chapter [6] pages 159-197, 39 p.
    - Chapter [7], pages 198-253, 56 p.
    - Chapter [8], pages 254-308, 55 p.
  - Wild Palms Chapters [9-10]>, TMs (carbon) 71 pages.
    - Chapter [9], pages 309-360, pages 54 p.
    - Chapter [10], pages 361-377, 17 p.
  - Wild Palms Chapters [1-3]>, AMsS 93 pages.
    - Chapter [1], pages 1-11, pages 11 p.
    - Chapter [2], pages 12-30, 19 p.
    - Chapter [3], pages 31-91, 63 p.
  - Wild Palms Chapters [4-8]>, AMsS 124 pages.
    - Chapter [4], pages 92-112, pages 21 p.
    - Chapter [5], pages 113-141, 29 p.
    - Chapter [6], pages 142-172, 32 p.
    - Chapter [7], pages 173-204, 32 p.
    - Chapter [8], pages 205-213, 10 p.
  - End Board, Wrapper n.d., 2 items
- II. Manuscripts
  - Notes on Being and Nothingness by Jean-Paul Sartre, in hand of W. Deseu. 1950 September 10, AMsS
  - "Address by WF at the Closing Plenary Session of the Seventh National Converence of the U.S. National Commission for UNESCO, in Denver," bearing a dedication "To my daughter, Jill" in his hand. 1959 October 2, TMs, mimeographed, 3 p.
  - Map, "CHECK POINTS" on hunt club race course n.d., AMs map, 1 p.
  - McCaslin-Compson-Snopes family chronology, 1813-1955 n.d., AMs, 1 p.
  - Genealogical chart of the McCaslin family, ca. 117-1904 n.d., AMs, 1 p.
  - "Omar's Eighteenth Quatrain" n.d., AMs, 11 p.
  - "The Peasants" n.d., AMs, 8 p.
  - Manuscript and partial typescripts of speech beginning "This award has to me a double value...," n.d., AMs, TMs, 6 p. w/env
  - Draft, opening of The Reiversn.d., AM draft, 1 p.
  - Dedication, "To my god-daughter Ann Barnwell Job" n.d., AMsS, 1 p.
  - Author's signature page for limited edition of The Unvanquishedn.d., 1 p. (237 of 250)
  - Autograph notes, including scrap of poetry, "When you and I beyond the veil have passed..." n.d., AMs, 2 p.
- III. Correspondence
  - W. Ross Brown affidavit [mock legal hand], in William Faulkner's hand and signed by him and others, regarding a trip in faulkner's plane 1941 January 4, ANS, 2 p.
  - Mississippi State Board of Health to William Faulkner [sic], enclosing copy of William Faulkner's birth certificate; and copies of Bible records regarding William faulkner's birth certificate; and copies of Bible records regarding the births of William Faulkner and Dean Swift Falkner 1942 January 30, TL, carbon, 1 p. w/ envelope
  - William Faulkner to Harold Ober 1942 July 28, TL, carbon telegraph, 1 p.
  - William Faulkner to H. N. Swanson 1942 July 28, TL, carbon, 1 p.
  - William Faulkner to "Dear Ruby," of First National Bank, Oxford, Mississippi 1942 July 30, TL, carbon, 1 p.
  - William Faulkner to James P. Avent 1943 August 9, TL, carbon, 2 p.
  - Tore Tallroth, Swedish Embassy, Washington, D.C., to William Faulkner, with article 1950 November 28, TLS
  - Mrs. Elton J. Warren to William Faulkner 1951 February 2, TLS
  - Linton [Massey] to Estelle [Faulkner] 1959 September 21, TLS, 1 p.
  - Donald [S. Klopfer] to William Faulkner 1962 June 21, TLS, 1 p. w/env.
  - William Faulkner to unknown, on Royal Air Force stationary, bearing sketch of William Faulkner in uniform [1919?], AL, 2 p.
  - William Faulkner to "Sirs" bearing on verso a partial TMS, with autograph corrections, of an address on human freedom n.y. September 14, TL, draft, 1 p.
  - [William Faulkner?] to "Bob, my dear boy" n.y. Thursday, TL, draft, 1 p.
  - William Faulkner to Mr. Geller, of Warner Brothers, regarding work in progress n.d., TN, 1 p.
  - William Faulkner to Whitney Oates, attached to envelop with negative of a child and woman enclosed n.d., ANS
  - William Faulkner to Mr. Herndon n.d., TL draft with autograph corrections, 1 p.
  - Autograph envelope addressed to "Paul Summers III Esq." 1958 October 29, AN
  - Autograph envelope bearing "Merry Xmas to Mother from Billy" in William Faulkner's hand n.d., AN
- IV. Printed Material
  - Newspaper articles and reviews regarding William Faulkner 1949-1979, ca. 200 items
  - Program for world premiere of Intruder in the Dust1949 October 11
  - Invitation to world premiere of Intruder in the Dust[1949] October 11
  - Brochure William Faulkner Man Working, announcing exhibition of William Faulkner's work at the University of Virginia Library 1959 October-December
  - Brochure Collected Stories of William Faulkner, announcing publication by Book-of-the-Month Club, Inc. n.d.
  - Broadside, "To the Voters of Oxford" n.d., 3 copies
  - Road Map and Guide for Oxford and Lafayette County n.d.